[MUSIC]
[음악]
>> We've now seen how cool deep learning can be.
딥러닝이 얼마나 훌륭한지 배웠습니다
We cannot apply it in a wide range of areas and
다양한 분야에 적용가능한데
yet we need high accuracy by learning really detailed features of our data, and
자세한 특징을 학습시켜 높은 정확도를 달성할 수 있죠
how your networks can support that.
신경망이 이를 도울 수 있고요
We've seen how it can be applied for
컴퓨터 비전에서의 다양한 이미지 분석 작업에
various tasks in image analysis in computer vision.
활용될 수 있음을 보았습니다
Let's now revisit the block diagram that we saw summarizing regression and
회귀와 분류 등의 기계학습 작업을 요약해서 보여주는
classification and other machinery tasks.
블록 다이어그램으로 돌아가 볼게요
How can be applied here for computer vision for deep learning?
딥러닝을 통한 컴퓨터 비전은 어떻게 적용돼야 할까요?
So in particular, let's talk about deep features for classifying images.
그중에서도 이미지 분류에 쓰이는 딥 특징을 알아봤습니다
So deep features for image classification.
이미지 분류를 위한 딥 특징
The input here are pairs of images with their labels.
입력은 라벨이 붙은 이미지 짝입니다
So, the labels that we've looked at were things like, whether there is a cat,
라벨은 고양이, 개, 주택 등의
the dog, a house or some other object in the image.
물체들이 있었습니다
And now, we feed that through the feature extractor.
특징 추출기에 집어넣습니다
In this case, we're using a deep learning model as a feature extractor.
딥러닝 모델을 특징 추출기로 쓰는 겁니다
So the output here, what we call the Deep features for
출력은 각각의 이미지에 대한
this particular image for every image.
딥 특징입니다
And now we feed in this images,
이제 대표적인 특징을
representative features through a machinery model.
기계학습 모델에 넣습니다
Where we use a simple classifier like logistic regression, in here.
로지스틱 회귀와 같은 간단한 분류기를 사용합니다
Say logistic regression as an example.
로지스틱 회귀라고 씁니다
And the output is our predicted labels.
결과값은 예측 라벨입니다
Predicted labels.
예측 라벨
And so we're going to feed in our predicted labels y hat and
예측 라벨 y^과 실제 라벨 y를
the true labels, y into our measure of quality.
품질 측정기에 넣습니다
So y and y hat, and the measure of quality depends on your task.
y와 y^, 품질 측정은 작업에 따라 다릅니다
For this task we use classification accuracy.
이때는 분류 정확도를 씁니다
And so the parameters
파라미터 w^은
w hat are really the parameters of the weights of the logistic regressive.
로지스틱 회귀의 가중치 파라미터입니다
So these are our weights on features.
특징에 대한 가중치죠
And what the machinery algorithm is gonna do, is take the classification accuracy,
기계학습 알고리즘은 이제 가중치 w^을 갱신해서
try to make a little better by changing those weights w hat and updating them.
분류 정확도를 향상시키려고 할 겁니다
We've now seen how deep learning can give you really cool and
딥러닝이 컴퓨터 비전의 다양한 작업에서
exciting results for a various tasks in computer vision.
뛰어난 성과를 낼 수 있다는 걸 봤습니다
And we saw those applied both two classification and
분류와 새로운 이미지 검색에
to retrieving of new images using raw neural networks as well as deep features.
단순 신경망과 딥 특징이 적용될 수 있음을 봤습니다
And our notebooks that we explored showed us that's
노트북에서 딥러닝 모델 구축과
really easy to build such deep learning models and
컴퓨터 비전의 기계학습 작업을
actually apply to really cool machine learning tasks in computer vision.
실제 적용하는 것도 쉬움을 확인했습니다
Both in classification and image retrieval which allows me to find exactly the kind
분류와 이미지 검색을 통해 정확히
of tools that I'm really excited about.
제가 원하는 신발을 찾았습니다
And with this you'll be able to build a really exciting intelligent application
이를 통해 기계학습에서 가장 많이 쓰이는
that uses one of the most sought after techniques today in machine learning,
딥러닝이란 기법을 활용한 똑똑한 애플리케이션을
deep learning.
만들 수 있게 될 것입니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]